[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [0, 3, 1, 4], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [1, 4, 3, 2], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to B?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to b2?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 0}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 20cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 20sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+N\u2082+20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081+N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082+20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+N\u2082+20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081+N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082+20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 20cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 20sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block along the incline?", "options": ["+50sin(45\u00b0)+T\u2081=5a\u2082", "-50sin(45\u00b0)+T\u2081=5a\u2082", "+50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "-50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to b1?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to B?", "options": ["N3 perpendicular up", "N3 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 up the incline ", "T\u2081 down the incline "], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 3, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block along the incline?", "options": ["+50sin(45\u00b0)+T\u2081=5a\u2082", "-50sin(45\u00b0)+T\u2081=5a\u2082", "+50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "-50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, N3, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 50cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 50sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2082+N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2082+N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2082+N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "-N\u2082+N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, N3, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 50cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 50sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+10=a\u2083", "-T\u2081+10=a\u2083", "+T\u2081-10=a\u2083", "-T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for blue block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on blue block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards", "T\u2081 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+10=a\u2083", "-T\u2081+10=a\u2083", "+T\u2081-10=a\u2083", "-T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: 10", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083", "Pink string: +a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2083: acceleration of blue block in y-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the pink string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string due to yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for pink string due to blue block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant", "l\u2081'' = +a\u2082", "l\u2082'' = -a\u2083"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083", "Pink string: +a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "type": "advance"}]}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= 84, a\u2082= -44, a\u2083= -4, T\u2081= 40, N\u2081= -15, N\u2083= 30", "a\u2081= 15, a\u2082= 70, a\u2083= -39, T\u2081= -20, N\u2081= 60, N\u2083= -21", "a\u2081= -4.93, a\u2082= -4.93, a\u2083= 4.95, T\u2081= 14.95, N\u2081= 14.08, N\u2083= -4.27", "a\u2081= -35, a\u2082= 70, a\u2083= 5, T\u2081= 75, N\u2081= -13, N\u2083= -44"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1000, "threejssubsubstep": 1000, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083", "Pink string: +a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, ", "Red block: 20sin(45\u00b0)=2a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-20cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: +50sin(45\u00b0)-T\u2081=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Blue block: +T\u2081-10=a\u2083", "Pink string: +a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= -4.93, a\u2082= -4.93, a\u2083= 4.95, T\u2081= 14.95, N\u2081= 14.08, N\u2083= -4.27"]}]}]